Here is the transformation framework. For a new function g of x equals
a times f of k times x minus d, plus c, the point
mapping is x prime equals x over k plus d, and y prime
equals a y plus c. Inside changes act horizontally on x; outside changes
act vertically on y. A negative a reflects across the x axis, and
a negative k reflects across the y axis.
Now, the problem. We are given g of x equals negative f of
minus x minus one, plus three, and the point one, negative two lies
on the graph of f. We will find its image under g.
Let us move to the coordinate plane and track the image step by step.
We begin at the point one, negative two on f.
First, reflect across the y axis. The
x coordinate changes sign; y is unchanged.
Next, translate one unit to the left.
Only the x coordinate decreases by one.
Now, reflect across the x axis. The
y coordinate changes sign; x is unchanged.
Finally, translate upward by three units. Only
the y coordinate increases by three.
Collecting all steps, the resulting point is negative two, five.